BIBEK OLI

hello@bibekoli.com, www.bibekoli.com

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Self-taught full stack developer with 5+ years of experience, specializing in the MERN stack and Next.js. Skilled in writing clean, maintainable code and creating visually appealing UIs. Quick to learn and adapt to new technologies.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- · Node.js
- React Native
- UI/ UX Design
- Redux & Zustand

- MongoDB
- MySQL
- · CSS3
- Material UI & Tailwind CSS
- Data Visualization
- · Clean Coding
- . GIT

WORK EXPERIENCE

Crystal Solution | Backend Developer

Mar 2024 - Present

- · Worked on building new and enhance existing features in Crystal School ERP.
- · Developed RESTful APIs for seamless integration with the mobile app.
- Improved the mobile app with new features and performance optimizations.

SproutGigs | Backend Engineer

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022

- Developed and implemented automated systems for user validation and submission processing to ensure data accuracy and efficiency.
- Optimized the backend to scale for high user traffic and data submissions.

Full Stack Freelance Developer

2019 - Present

- Worked on various web apps including portfolios, blogs, e-commerce, and educational platforms.
- Developed frontend and backend systems for seamless user experiences.

EDUCATION

Mechi Multiple Campus (Bachelors)

2019 - 2024

Bachelors' in Computer Application

Nidi Secondary School (+2)

2017 - 2019

Computer Science

INTERESTS

- GraphQL APIs
- Single Page Applications (SPA)
- e-Commerce

- Artificial Intelligence and Automation
- · Graphics Design
- Cosmology

Arocel

URL: arocel.com, app.arocel.com, bibekcollexn.arocelshop.com

- A platform for creating e-commerce websites within minutes.
- It includes a landing page, a admin dashboard for managing online stores and ecommerce website that renders stores based on current store domain.

DuoTunes

URL: duotunes.bibekoli.com

 A music player app made with React Native that can play multiple songs on each side of earphone/ speaker along with more awesome features.

ResQNest (Platform for Animal Rescue and Adoption)

URL: resquest.bibekoli.com

- · A platform for connecting animal rescuers, adopters and rescue centers.
- Post and browse animals list for rescue and adoption.

BechnuParyo (A P2P Marketplace)

URL: bechnuparyo.bibekoli.com

- A P2P buying and selling platform connecting sellers and buyers.
- Built using NextJS, MongoDB and realtime one-to-one chat system using Socket.io.

Limited Sneakers (Online Sneakers Store)

URL: sneakers.bibekoli.com

- An e-commerce applications for Sneakers shop.
- · Includes an admin panel for managing products and orders.

Online Ticketing System

URL: na

- A FERN Stack application for searching and booking online tickets.
- · Got a good opportunity to learn these technologies.

Useful Online Tools

URL: tools.bibekoli.com

· A collection of useful online tools for developers.